Hello, and welcome to Lesson 40
你好，欢迎来到第40课
of this introduction to calculus with Wolfram U.
的这个微积分导论与Wolfram U。
The topic for this lesson is part 2 of a sample calculus exam.
本节课的题目是微积分考试样题的第二部分。
Let’s begin with a brief overview of the lesson.
我们先来简单介绍一下本课的内容。
Like I said earlier on, this is the second part of the calculus exam
就像我前面说的，这是微积分考试的第二部分。
that I’ll present now.
我现在要介绍的。
As in part 1, which we presented last time,
正如我们上次介绍的第一部分。
the questions over here are very similar to what you might find
这里的问题和你可能会发现的问题非常相似。
on the AP Calculus AB exam, but of course the questions over here
在AP微积分AB考试中，但当然这里的问题
will be somewhat more difficult than the ones in the first part.
会比第一部分的难度大一些。
In fact, there are a couple of them which are really quite involved.
其实，其中有几项真的很有讲究。
I’ll warn you a little more at that time,
到时候我再提醒你一下。
but do pay careful attention.
但要仔细注意。
This is the hard part of the exam.
这是考试的难点。
Let’s begin with question 14, where we left off last time.
我们先从问题14开始，也就是我们上次离开的地方。
The question is calculate the limit
本题是计算极限
of this expression over here at h = 0.
在h=0时，这个表达式在这里。
Now the point is that it looks like a limit, no doubt,
现在的问题是，它看起来像一个极限，毫无疑问。
but if you look at the expression very carefully,
但如果你仔细观察表情。
it’s really a derivative,
这其实是一个衍生品。
and in fact, it’s a derivative of Sec[x] at π/3—
而事实上，它是Sec[x]在π/3-的导数。
after all, it’s like f[x] + h – f[x]/h.
毕竟，这就像f[x]+h-f[x]/h。
If you work out the derivative of secant,
如果你计算出secant的导数。
that’s secant times tangent,
那是Srecant的时代切线。
so you would expect the answer to be 2√3.
所以你会期望答案是2√3。
Let’s check that with D.
让我们和D一起检查一下。
You find the derivative of Sec[x] and plug in x as π/3,
你找到Sec[x]的导数，并将x插入π/3。
and you do get back the expected answer.
而你确实得到了预期的答案。
Or you could use Limit and find the answer,
或者你可以使用Limit，找到答案。
and you get back just the same result.
而你得到的只是同样的结果。
Let’s move on to question 15, which says that a disk was measured
我们接着看问题15，问题15说，测量了一个圆盘。
to have a radius of 9 cm.
要有9厘米的半径。
The error was around 0.04 cm.
误差在0.04厘米左右。
The question is find the error in the area.
本题是找到该区域的错误。
You’ve got two variables—you’ve got the radius and the area—
你有两个变量，你有半径和面积。
and they are related by A = πr^2.
且它们之间的关系为A=πr^2。
Now if that’s the relation, then the differentials, the errors
如果是这样的关系，那么微分，误差... ...
are related by dA = 2πrdr by taking derivatives,
由dA=2πrdr取导数相关。
so what you do is you recall that from the information given to you,
所以，你要做的是，你要从给你的信息中回忆起来。
that r is 9, dr is 0.04—that’s the error—so now the error in the area
r是9，dr是0.04--这就是误差--所以现在该区域的误差。
would be 2π times r times dr, and so the answer is 2.26 roughly.
将是2π乘以r乘以dr，所以答案大致为2.26。
Okay. On to number 16, which says find the derivative of Log[x^2 – 3].
好了，现在到了第16题，题目是求Log[&lt;i&gt;x&lt;/i&gt;^2 -3]的导数。第16题，求Log[x^2 -3]的导数。
Now that looks like something for which you need the chain rule,
现在看来，你需要链式规则的东西。
so what you do is you find the derivative of log,
所以你要做的就是找到对数的导数。
which is 1/(x^2 – 3),
即1/(x^2 - 3)。
and then multiply by the derivative of x^2 – 3, which is 2x.
再乘以x^2 - 3的导数，即2x。
That’s the final answer.
这就是最后的答案。
You can check it with D, and you do get back just the same result.
你可以用D来检查，确实得到的结果是一样的。
On to number 17, which says calculate the third derivative
到了第17条，它说计算第三个导数。
of the expression over here, 3x^4 – Cos[x] + e^2x.
的表达式在这里，3x^4 - Cos[x] + e^2x。
What you do is you work out the first derivative,
你要做的是计算出第一个导数。
which is 12x^3 from 3x^4, plus Sin[x] from the second term
由3x^4得12x^3，再加上第二项的Sin[x]。
and 2e^2x from the third term.
和2e^2x从第三项。
Check that with D, then start here and work out the second derivative,
用D来检查，然后从这里开始计算出第二个导数。
which is Cos[x] from the Sin[x], then 36x^2 from the from the 12x^3
由Sin[x]得Cos[x]，再由36x^2得12x^3。
and 4e^2x from the first term over here.
和4e^2x从这边的第一项。
Let’s check that with D again, the second derivative,
我们再用D检查一下，第二个导数。
then work out the third derivative
然后求出第三个导数
as the derivative of this expression over here.
作为这个表达式的导数在这里。
Then you get back –Sin[x] from the Cos[x],
然后你从Cos[x]中得到-Sin[x]。
you get back 72x from here
你从这里回来72x。
and you get back an 8e^2x from the first term.
你可以从第一项中得到一个8e^2x。
Then you check that with D, taking the third derivative,
然后你用D检查，取第三个导数。
and you get back the answer.
而你得到的答案。
Okay. On to number 18, which says that the region bounded by x + 2
好了，现在说说第18条，该条规定，由&lt;i&gt;x&lt;/i&gt;+2为界的区域在18号，它说，该区域的边界由x+2。
and the quadratic over here is rotated around the x axis.
而这边的二次元是围绕x轴旋转的。
The question is to find the volume of the solid
问题是要找到固体的体积。
made by this rotation.
这次轮换所做的。
Here is a plot.
这是一个情节。
You have a straight line and a parabola, an upward parabola,
你有一条直线和一条抛物线，一条向上的抛物线。
and the question is where do these two intersect?
而问题是这两者的交叉点在哪里？
Well, what you do is you use Solve
好吧，你要做的是你用Solve
and find out where the straight line and the curve intersect.
并找出直线和曲线的交点。
You get a lower limit and an upper limit.
你会得到一个下限和一个上限。
Now if you let f be the first function and g be the second function,
现在如果让f是第一个函数，g是第二个函数。
then clearly f is below g.
那么显然f在g之下。
Because you are rotating around the x axis,
因为你是围绕x轴旋转的。
you might want to use the washer method over here.
你可能会想在这里使用洗衣机的方法。
That tells you you must use π(g(x)^2 – f(x)^2)dx inside.
这就告诉你必须用π(g(x)^2-f(x)^2)dx里面。
If you do the integral over here using Integrate,
如果你在这里用Integrate做积分。
you get back the final answer for the problem.
你会得到问题的最终答案。
On to number 19, which says find the limit of this quotient over here.
到了19号，上面写着在这里找到这个商的极限。
Now as a first step, what you could do is you’re working at 0,
现在作为第一步，你可以做的是你在0。
so you plug in 0 for both the numerator and the denominator,
所以你把分子和分母都插入0。
and what you find is that in fact, you have a 0/0 situation.
而你发现的是，其实你的情况是0/0。
That’s an indeterminacy,
这是一个不确定的问题。
so that should remind you of L’Hospital’s rule,
所以这应该提醒你L'Hospital的规则。
which says that you work out the derivatives of
它说你要计算出以下的导数
the numerator and denominator separately,
分别计算分子和分母。
plug in x goes to 0, and you get back 5/3,
插上x到0，就能得到5/3。
which is the correct answer, as you can check with Limit.
这是正确的答案，因为你可以用Limit检查。
Here is a plot which confirms that you indeed have
这里有一张图，可以证实你确实有。
the correct answer for the limit.
限的正确答案。
On to number 20, which says to calculate
到了第20条，它说要计算出
the integral over here from 2 to 3.
这里的积分从2到3。
Now that looks like the case of the substitution rule
现在看来，这像是替代规则的情况
because you need to put the denominator u equal to x^2 – 1.
因为你需要把分母u等于x^2 - 1。
If you work out the derivative, you get du = 2xdx.
如果你计算出导数，你会得到du=2xdx。
Then you need to change the endpoints—
然后你需要改变端点---。
after all, you’re going from x to u.
毕竟，你要从x到u。
When x is 2, then u is 3.
当x为2时，则u为3。
When x is 3, then 3^2 – 1 is 8,
当x为3时，则3^2-1为8。
so that’s the new integral over here,
所以这是新的积分在这里。
which turns out to be 3/2 * Log[8/3].
结果是3/2 * Log[8/3]。
You can check the answer with Integrate,
你可以用Integrate检查答案。
and you do get back just the same result.
而你得到的只是同样的结果。
Here is a plot which shows the area which you just computed.
这里有一张图，显示了你刚才计算的面积。
On to number 21, which says find y' if y^2 + x * y = 2.
到了第21题，说如果y^2+x*y=2，就找y'。
The point is because you need to work with y^2,
问题的关键在于你需要用y^2来工作。
we should use implicit differentiation.
我们应该使用隐性区分法。
What you do is you work out the derivative
你要做的是计算出导数
of each term in the equation separately.
方程中每个项的分别。
That’s the derivative of y^2,
这就是y^2的导数。
and the second term over here has got
和第二任期在这里已经得到了
a derivative with the product rule,
乘积规则的导数。
and of course the right-hand side has the derivative 0.
当然右边的导数为0。
You work out the derivative for each term separately,
你分别计算出每项的导数。
so you get 2ydy/dx from here,
所以你从这里得到2ydy/dx。
and then you try and simplify the answer.
然后你再尝试简化答案。
You get dy/dx = –y(2y + x).
你得到dy/dx=-y(2y+x)。
Of course you can do the same thing in the Wolfram Language,
当然你也可以在Wolfram语言中做同样的事情。
and you get back the value for y' at the point (x, y),
而你得到的是y'在该点的值(x, y)。
which is –y[x]/(x + 2y[x]).
即-y[x]/(x+2y[x])。
On to number 22, which says find the equation
到了第22条，它说要找到方程。
of the normal to this curve at (–2, –4).
在(-2，-4)处，这个曲线的法线。
Now keep in mind that the normal is really
现在请记住，正常的是真正的
the perpendicular to the curve at the point,
曲线在该点的垂直度。
so you first work out the slope at that point.
所以你首先要在这一点上计算出坡度。
When I say slope, I mean the derivative,
我说的斜率，是指导数。
and the derivative of this curve is just x + 3,
而这条曲线的导数只是x+3。
so you plug in the value for x and you get the slope as 1.
所以你插入x的值，你得到的斜率为1。
But that’s for the tangent,
但这是为了切磋。
so the normal line will have slope –1 from here.
所以，从这里开始，法线的斜率将为-1。
You write down the equation of the normal at that point,
你把这时的法线方程写下来。
and you get the equation y = –x – 6.
你可以得到公式y=-x-6。
Here is a plot which shows the given normal.
下面是一张显示给定法线的图。
You have the curve over here and the normal over there.
这边是曲线，那边是正常。
Okay. On to number 23, which says for what value of a and b
好了，现在说说第23条，它说的是&lt;i&gt;a&lt;/i&gt;和&lt;i&gt;b&lt;/I&gt;的值是多少。关于第23条，它说，对于什么值的a和b。
will this function over here become differentiable?
这边的函数会不会变得可分化？
Basically you have a piecewise function
基本上，你有一个计件函数
because there are two pieces over here,
因为这边有两块。
and they both meet at –1 provided a and b have got the right values.
并且它们都在-1处相遇，条件是a和b有正确的值。
Now you want your function to be differentiable,
现在，你希望你的函数是可区分的。
so there are two conditions.
所以有两个条件。
First of all, the left-hand derivative at –1
首先，在-1处的左手导数。
should equal the right-hand derivative, and secondly,
应等于右边的导数，其次。
the left-hand limit at –1 should equal the right-hand limit.
左手极限在-1处应等于右手极限。
Now for the first condition, if you differentiate over here,
现在对于第一个条件，如果你在这边区分。
you get a = 3b(–1)^2 – 4(–1),
你得到a=3b(-1)^2 - 4(-1)。
and the second relation over here for the limits
和第二种关系在这里的极限
will just be obtained by putting in x = –1.
只需将x=-1，就可以得到。
You solve those two for a and b,
你解决这两个a和b。
so that says that a is 11/2 and b is 1/2.
所以说a是11/2，b是1/2。
Then the function is differentiable.
那么这个函数是可微分的。
Here is the graph of this function,
这是这个函数的图形。
and you can see that it’s nice and smooth at the required point, –1.
你可以看到它在所需的点-1处很平滑。
On to number 24, which says a particle moves
在24号，它说一个粒子的运动
according to the velocity v(t) = 4sin(t)cos(t).
根据速度v(t)=4sin(t)cos(t)。
The question is find the total distance that it travels
这道题是求出它所走的总路程。
from 0 to π in seconds.
从0到π，以秒为单位。
To do that you must work out the integral,
要做到这一点，你必须计算出积分。
but you must ignore the sign because you want a distance,
但你一定要忽略这个标志，因为你要的是距离。
so you have an absolute value over here.
所以你在这里有一个绝对值。
Use the Integrate function with the absolute value,
使用绝对值的积分函数。
and you get back the answer as 4.
而你得到的答案是4。
Here’s a plot which shows the distance that you have found.
这里有一张图，可以显示你找到的距离。
Of course keep in mind that the negative area, in this case,
当然要记住，在这种情况下，负面积。
was counted as positive because we want the distance traveled.
被算作正数，因为我们要的是行进的距离。
On to one of the most difficult questions for this exam, number 25,
到了本次考试最难的一道题，25号。
that will occupy two slides, so do pay careful attention.
将占据两张幻灯片，所以要仔细注意。
The question is a cylindrical can has got a volume of 216 cm^3.
本题是一个圆柱形罐子的体积是216cm^3，请问它的体积是多少？
The question is find a value for the radius
问题是找到一个半径的值。
that will minimize the amount of material used.
这将使材料的使用量降到最低。
Now if you make a can, then the material will cover the surface,
现在如果你做一个罐头，那么材料会覆盖在表面。
so you’re talking about surface area of the can.
所以你说的是罐子的表面积。
Now surface area has got two parts.
现在表面积有两个部分。
One is the top and bottom areas, which give you 2πr^2,
一个是上下两个区域，给你2πr^2。
and the side area, which is 2πrh,
和侧面积，即2πrh。
so the total surface area is 2πrh + 2πr^2.
所以总表面积为2πrh+2πr^2。
But keep in mind that you have two variables, r and h,
但请记住，你有两个变量，r和h。
so you must eliminate one of them.
所以你必须消除其中的一个。
You know that πr^2h is 216—after all, that’s given to you over here.
你知道πr^2h是216--毕竟这是在这边给你的。
You can solve for h in terms of r,
你可以用r来求解h。
and now the surface area no longer depends upon h.
现在表面积不再取决于h。
It only depends upon r,
它只取决于r。
and that is the starting point for the second part of the problem.
而这也是问题第二部分的出发点。
Now what we do is we start with the expression for the surface area
现在我们要做的是，我们从表面积的表达式入手
and try and minimize it with respect to r.
并尽量减少它对r的影响。
What you do is you take the derivative, set it equal to 0
你要做的是取导数，将其设为0。
and you solve, and you get back r as roughly 3.25
而你解，你得到的r大约是3.25。
and exactly it is 3 times the cubed root of 4/π.
而恰恰它是4/π的立方根的3倍。
Now let’s check that you have a minimum,
现在让我们检查一下你是否有最低限度的。
so work out the second derivative at that value of r.
所以求出该值r的二次导数。
It looks positive, so you have a minimum.
它看起来是积极的，所以你有一个最低限度。
Basically the can will use the least amount of material
基本上，罐头将使用最少的材料。
when the radius is around 3.25 cm.
当半径在3.25厘米左右时。
On to the final question for the exam, this sample exam.
到了考试的最后一道题，这次抽考。
You have a spherical balloon that’s losing air at a certain rate.
你有一个球形气球，以一定的速度失去空气。
The question is find the rate at which the radius is decreasing
本题是求出半径减小的速度。
when the radius is 10 cm.
当半径为10厘米时。
Now keep in mind that you actually have a relation
现在请记住，你实际上有一个关系
volume and radius, which is V = 4πr^3/3 for the sphere.
体积和半径，对于球体来说，就是V=4πr^3/3。
If you find the derivative, you get dV/dt from there
如果你找到了导数，你可以从那里得到dV/dt。
equal to 4πr^2 dr/dt.
等于4πr^2 dr/dt。
That’s just the differential version of the relation.
这只是关系的微分版本。
Okay. Now you know the value of dV/dt as –2,
好了，现在你知道了&lt;i&gt;dV&lt;/i&gt;/&lt;i&gt;dt&lt;/i&gt;的值为-2，那么，你就知道了。现在你知道dV/dt的值为-2。
so you can work out the value of dr/dt by solving,
所以你可以通过求解来计算出dr/dt的值。
and you get back the answer as –1/200π.
而你得到的答案是-1/200π。
The radius is decreasing—after all, you have a negative answer—
半径是递减的--毕竟，你有一个否定的答案--。
at a rate of 1/200π cm/sec.
以1/200π厘米/秒的速度。
Okay. That brings me to the end of this sample exam,
好了，我就到此为止了。本次样板考试到此结束。
and also to the end of the course.
也到了课程结束的时候。
It’s been a great pleasure to teach you.
很高兴能教你。
From here on, we wish you all the best.
从这里开始，我们祝愿你一切顺利。
From all of us here at Wolfram U,
我们沃尔夫兰大学的所有人都这么说。
good luck, and thank you.
这节课到这就结束了 谢谢观看